const e={sections:[{header:{text:"Put these sentences in indirect speech"},exercises:[{type:"test",question:'"What do you mean by that?" said Aruzhan.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Aruzhan asked what I meant by that.",2:"Aruzhan asked what did I mean by that.",3:"Aruzhan asked what I did mean by that."}},{type:"test",question:'"What do you want me to say?" Damir said.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Damir asked what I wanted him to say.",2:"Damir asked what do I want him to say.",3:"Damir asked I wanted to say him what."}},{type:"test",question:'"How long does it take you to get to college, Masha" said Vanya.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Vanya asked Masha how long it took her to get to college.",2:"Vanya asked Masha how long did it take her to get to college.",3:"Vanya asked Masha if it took long to get to college."}},{type:"test",question:'"Why do you cry, Willy" said the teacher.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The teacher asked Willy why he cried.",2:"The teacher asked Willy why did he cry.",3:"The teacher asked Willy not to cry."}},{type:"test",question:'"What are you laughing at, Mira?" asked Marat.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Marat asked Mira what she was laughing at.",2:"Marat asked Mira why she was laughing.",3:"Marat asked Mira what she is laughing at."}},{type:"test",question:'"Where is your friend?" said the child.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The child asked where my friend was.",2:"The child asked where my friend is.",3:"The child asked where was my friend."}},{type:"test",question:'"Where are you going?" asks Mother.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Mother asks where I am going.",2:"Mother asks where I was going.",3:"Mother asks where was I going."}},{type:"test",question:'"What has happened to his son?" asked the doctor.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The doctor asked what had happened to his son.",2:"The doctor asked what happened to his son.",3:"The doctor asked did something happen to his son."}},{type:"test",question:`The old lady said, "Why haven't you seen me all this time?"`,rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The old lady asked why he hadn't seen her all that time.",2:"The old lady asked why didn't he see her all that time.",3:"The old lady asked why he didn't see her all that time."}},{type:"test",question:'He said, "What have you found, Lena?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"He asked Lena what she had found.",2:"He asked Lena if she had found something.",3:"He asked Lena what did she find."}},{type:"test",question:'"Where were you last night?" he said.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"He asked where we had been the previous night.",2:"He asked where we were the previous night.",3:"He asked where were we the previous night."}},{type:"test",question:'"When did it all happen?" she asked.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"She asked when it all had happened.",2:"She asked when it all did happen.",3:"She asked when it all happened."}},{type:"test",question:'"How many times has he been there?" said Vasilisa.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Vasilisa asked how many times he had been there.",2:"Vasilisa asked how many times he has been there.",3:"Vasilisa asked how many times he was there."}},{type:"test",question:'"Why have you missed so many classes this week, Temirlan?" the teacher said.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The teacher asked Temirlan why he had missed so many classes that week.",2:"The teacher asked Temirlan why he missed so many classes that week.",3:"The teacher asked Temirlan why had he missed so many classes that week."}},{type:"test",question:'"How long have they been married?" asked Anna.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Anna asked how long they had been married.",2:"Anna asked how long have they been married.",3:"Anna asked how long had they been married."}}]}]};export{e as default};
